<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jeffrey Luppes - Cloud</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/cloud.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-12-22T22:42:45+01:00</updated><subtitle>Machine Learning Engineer and Data Scientist</subtitle><entry><title>Google Cloud Platform Certified Data Engineer</title><link href="/google-cloud-platform-certified-data-engineer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-22T22:42:45+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-22T22:42:45+01:00</updated><author><name>Jeffrey Luppes</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-12-22:/google-cloud-platform-certified-data-engineer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GCP data Engineer!" src="/images/gcp_data_engineer.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoooo! I passed the GCP data engineer exam. In truth, I am not really a data engineer.. but it is a role I can fill and I strongly feel that as a data scientist you should be able to have a solid grasp of engineering too, or at least understand …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GCP data Engineer!" src="/images/gcp_data_engineer.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoooo! I passed the GCP data engineer exam. In truth, I am not really a data engineer.. but it is a role I can fill and I strongly feel that as a data scientist you should be able to have a solid grasp of engineering too, or at least understand it well enough to know what the challenges are. The exam was about 2 hours long and is supposed to be roughly equivalent to the AWS professional level certifications. Funny enough, it actually covers a lot of the ML engineering topics. Perhaps there's a ML exam in the works?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Update: As of 2020 there is now a GCP Machine Learning certification. I passed it in 2021. You can read more about it &lt;a href="https://medium.com/towards-data-science/a-comprehensive-study-guide-for-the-google-professional-machine-learning-engineer-certification-1e411db4d2cf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose I got lucky with the matter. I've been working with GCP for about a year now and I've mostly been involved whenever there's a ML demand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for studying strategies: I had a four-day training back in August. After that, I spent about 20 hours doing coursera courses and about 16 studying with the exam guide as my guideline. Particularly the last part was vital. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check out the certification here: https://www.credential.net/a015b522-77d3-48c0-b7f7-16c9948a9ac4&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Cloud"></category><category term="GCP"></category><category term="Programming"></category><category term="Google"></category><category term="Certifications"></category></entry></feed>